In this American English pronunciation video,
在这段美式英语发音视频中，
we're going to learn how to make the R consonant sound.
我们将学习如何发出 R 辅音音。
This is truly one of the hardest sounds in American English.
这确实是美式英语中最难的音之一。
Before I go into how to make it,
在我讲解如何发这个音之前，
I want to talk about how not to make it.
我想先谈谈如何不发这个音。
In many languages, the R is made by bouncing the front part of the tongue against the roof of the mouth,
在许多语言中，R 是通过将舌头的前部弹到上颚来发出的，
rr, rr.
rr, rr。
In American English, this sound is the T or D between vowels,
在美式英语中，这个音是元音之间的 T 或 D，
but it's quite different from the American R.
但它与美式 R 相差甚远。
Rrr.
Rrr。
You can't hold out rr, rr,
你不能拖长 rr, rr，
but you should be able to hold out the American R.
但你应该能够拖长美式 R。
Rrr.
Rrr。
This consonant is voiced.
这个辅音是有声的。
There are two ways to make this sound.
有两种方法可以发出这个音。
In the first way,
第一种方法中，
the front part of the tongue pulls back and up,
舌头的前部向后并向上拉，
like this.
像这样。
It's fatter and thicker,
它变得更胖更厚，
and that's what we want here.
这就是我们想要的效果。
We're making the tongue fatter and thicker so it's not as long.
我们让舌头变得更胖更厚，这样它就不那么长了。
The back doesn't move.
后部不动。
This is happening with the front and middle of the tongue.
这是舌头的前部和中部在发生变化。
The middle part of the tongue lifts up towards the roof of the mouth.
舌头的中部抬起，靠近上颚。
You can touch the sides of the tongue to the sides of the roof of the mouth here,
你可以让舌头的两侧接触上颚的两侧，
or to the inside or bottom of the side teeth,
或者接触侧牙的内侧或底部，
here.
在这里。
The front part of the tongue is hanging in the middle of the mouth,
舌头的前部悬在口腔中间，
not touching anything.
不接触任何东西。
This sound is forward and focused because of the position of the lips.
由于嘴唇的位置，这个音是向前和集中的。
The corners come in,
嘴角收拢，
pushing the lips away from the face.
将嘴唇推离面部。
This lip position will be a little more relaxed when the R comes at the end of a syllable.
当 R 出现在音节末尾时，这种嘴唇位置会稍微放松一些。
With the other way,
另一种方法是，
to make an R, on the right.
在右边发 R。
The R can also be made by flipping the tongue tip up.
R 也可以通过将舌尖翻上来发出。
The lips flare the same way.
嘴唇以同样的方式张开。
Some native speakers make the R one way,
一些母语者用一种方法发 R，
and some the other.
而另一些用另一种方法。
Native speakers get the correct sound no matter the mouth position.
无论口腔位置如何，母语者都能发出正确的音。
But I've found that non-native speakers often drop the jaw too much in this second method,
但我发现，非母语者在使用第二种方法时，往往下巴掉得太多，
and it makes the sound hollow.
这使得声音空洞。
Rrr.
Rrr。
The jaw doesn't need to drop very much for this sound.
这个音不需要下巴掉得太多。
Rrr.
Rrr。
So keep this in mind as you work on one of these two methods.
所以在练习这两种方法之一时要记住这一点。
Here's the R sound on its own,
这是 R 音本身，
not part of a word.
不是单词的一部分。
You can see the lips flare.
你可以看到嘴唇张开。
Think of creating a little space between the inside of your lips and your teeth.
想象在嘴唇内侧和牙齿之间创造一点空间。
Notice how little jaw drop there is.
注意下巴掉得有多小。
We don't need to drop the jaw to pull the tongue back and up.
我们不需要下巴掉下来就能把舌头向后和向上拉。
The word rest.
单词 rest。
When the R is at the beginning of a word,
当 R 在单词开头时，
we tend to make the lips a tight circle.
我们倾向于让嘴唇形成一个紧的圆圈。
Again, little jaw drop as the middle of the tongue lifts to the roof of the mouth.
同样，当舌头的中部抬到上颚时，下巴掉得很少。
The word proud.
单词 proud。
When R is in a beginning consonant cluster,
当 R 在开头的辅音群中时，
the lips may not be as tight as in a beginning R.
嘴唇可能不像开头 R 那样紧。
The word mother.
单词 mother。
At the end of a syllable,
在音节末尾，
the lip position for the R is definitely more relaxed than a beginning R,
R 的嘴唇位置肯定比开头 R 更放松，
but the lips still flare.
但嘴唇仍然张开。
Here,
在这里，
we compare the lip position of the beginning R in rest,
我们比较了单词 rest 中开头 R 的嘴唇位置，
above,
在上面，
to the ending R in mother, below.
和单词 mother 中结尾 R 的嘴唇位置，在下面。
The ending R lip position is much more relaxed.
结尾 R 的嘴唇位置要放松得多。
Thinking about the lip position will help you make a better R sound.
考虑嘴唇的位置将帮助你发出更好的 R 音。
As you work on this consonant,
在练习这个辅音时，
practice very slowly, thinking about all three things at once.
要非常慢地练习，同时考虑这三件事。
Very little jaw drop.
下巴掉得很少。
The tongue position, and the lip position.
舌头的位置和嘴唇的位置。
Remember, you can hold out this sound,
记住，你可以拖长这个音，
so that's how you want to practice it.
所以你要这样练习它。
Rrrrr.
Rrrrr。
Hold it out for five or ten seconds.
拖长五到十秒。
Hold it out as long as you can.
尽可能长地拖长。
When you practice it in a word, do the same.
当你在单词中练习时，也要这样做。
Rrrrrrest.
Rrrrrrest。
Proud.
Proud。
Motherrrrrr.
Motherrrrrr。
The R sound.
R 音。
Rest.
Rest。
Proud.
Proud。
Mother.
Mother。
Example words.
示例单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Read.
Read。
Rrr.
Rrr。
Read.
Read。
Great.
Great。
Rrr.
Rrr。
Great.
Great。
Try.
Try。
Rrr.
Rrr。
Try.
Try。
Later.
Later。
Rrr.
Rrr。
Later.
Later。
Write.
Write。
Rrr.
Rrr。
Write.
Write。
Other.
Other。
Rrr.
Rrr。
Other.
Other。